In this clip I'm going to talk about another skin type that needs to exfoliate a lot.
That's acneic skin.
Acneic skin meaning breakouts, blackheads, pimples.
It is so important to exfoliate but it's important to have you exfoliate when you have acneic skin.
You're going to want to use, if you're oily with blackheads, you're going to want to use a more granular scrub like the Skin Prep Scrub that has the cornmeal that we used earlier.
This is a rougher scrub.
The skin is thicker.
It can handle it.
You certainly wouldn't want to use this on the sensitive skin.
The reason why we want to be more aggressive is really want to loosen those dead skin cells and allow the blackheads to release.
If you are someone who had pustules and infected acne, you'd want to go for something more like the microfoliant which is the rice bran exfoliant which is going to be gentle because if you came on this skin with a rough scrub, you can break the skin and spread infection and bacteria and you'll get the opposite result that you desire.
You want to use something that also contains salicylic acid which is an antibacterial agent.